Guide to the Benjamin Newton Duke Papers, 1834-1969, bulk 1890-1929. RL.00328
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Business, 1880, 1890-1919, and undated; 2.5 Linear Feet
  - Railroads: Southern Railway Company, 1906, 1909, 1915 (Box 131)
  - Railroads: miscellaneous, 1904-1916; 3 folders (Box 131)
  - Real estate: miscellaneous, 1901-1903, 1907, 1912-1915; 2 folders (Box 131)
  - Tobacco: American Snuff Company, 1904-1915 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: American Tobacco Company, 1890, 1903-1915 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: American Tobacco Company, Code No. 6 (codebook), 1902 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: American Tobacco Company: formulas for tobacco and cigarette flavorings, 1896, August (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: British-American Tobacco Company, 1912-1915 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: George W. Helme Company, 1911-1915 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: Liggett and Meyers Tobacco Company, 1911-1915, 1918 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: P. Lorillard Company, 1911-1914 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: Porto Rican American Tobacco Company, 1912-1914 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company, 1912-1915 (Box 132)
  - Tobacco: miscellaneous, 1880, 1901, 1903, 1912-1915, 1918, and undated; 2 folders (Box 132)
  - Alaska Dredging and Power Company: minute book, 1907-1908 (Box 132)
  - Alaska Dredging and Power Company: meeting proxy, 1907 November (Box 132)
  - Alaska Dredging and Power Company: stock certificates book, 1907 (Box 132)
  - Cary Lumber Company, 1898, 1904-1905, 1909, and undated (Box 133)
  - Durham Buggy Company, 1908, 1913 (Box 133)
  - Durham [W. T. Carrington] Lumber Company, 1908, 1912, 1914 (Box 133)
  - Fort Smith Wholesale Grocery Co., 1902-1903, 1907-1909 (Box 133)
  - Lincoln Lithia Water Co., 1899-1905, 1907 (Box 133)
  - Manufacturers' Record Publishing Co., 1906-1909, 1912 (Box 133)
  - Seward Dredging Company, 1912 (Box 133)
  - Solomon River Hydraulic Mining Company: certificate of incorporation, by-laws, minutes, 1905; 1 Volumes (Box 133)
  - Solomon River Hydraulic Mining Company: certificates of incorporation (2 versions), 1905 (Box 133)
  - Solomon River Hydraulic Mining Company: contracts and agreements, 1905-1907 (Box 133)
  - Solomon River Hydraulic Mining Company: stock certificate books, 1905 (Box 133)
  - Solomon River Hydraulic Mining Company: stock certificates, 1905 (Box 133)
  - Southern Car Company, 1912, 1915 (Box 133)
  - Southern Finishing and Warehouse Company, 1895 (Box 133)
  - Standard Pure Food Stores, Inc., 1914 (Box 133)
  - Unites States Rubber Co., 1913-1914 (Box 133)
  - Virginia-Carolina Chemical Company, 1900-1915 (Box 133)
  - Wayne Hardwood Company, 1913 (Box 133)
  - Miscellaneous circulars, reports, prospectuses, 1895, 1898, 1903-1915, and undated (Box 133)
- Personal, 1877-1937 and undated; 5.5 Linear Feet
  The Personal series is arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
  This series contains material related to the personal interests of Benjamin N. Duke and his immediate family. It includes Sarah P. Duke's diary (1927-1929) and recipes; genealogical material; honorary degree certificates; a B. N. Duke suit pattern; a scrapbook of the condolences sent to the Duke family upon the death of B. N. Duke; and other material pertaining to funerals, memorials, and tributes to B. N. Duke, Sarah P. Duke, James B. Duke, and Angier B. Duke. The series also contains printed materials, including a bible, cookbook, poetry volumes, and pamphlets and resolutions related to Benjamin N. Duke's philanthropic activities.
  - Alpha Tau Omega fraternity: report and student forms, 1903-1904 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    Includes report of Virginia Delta Chapter (University of Virginia) to Plato T. Durham, Provincial Chief, and approved applications by students for membership in the Beta Xi (College of Charleston, SC), Alpha Delta (University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill), and Xi (Trinity College) chapters of the fraternity.
  - Bible, circa 1870s? and accompanying letter, C.L. Mitchell to R.L. Flowers, 1925 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Bible, circa 1880s (Box 167)
  - Clippings, 1892-1904, 1908 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1911-1914 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1919-1935 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1936 (Box 136, Folder 6)
    Obituaries for Sarah P. Duke.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Clippings scrapbook, 1877, 1890-1902, and undated (Box 140)
    Clippings of articles related to the Duke family and their acquaintences as well as domestic advice columns and articles about Trinity College. Includes wedding and anniversary announcements for Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah P. Duke, a wedding announcement for Brodie L. Duke, and obituaries for Mary E. Lyon and George Washington Duke.
  - Duke, Angier B.: memorials, 1923-1924 (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - Duke, Angier B.: memorials: Plato T. Durham poem and reactions, 1923-1924 (Box 136, Folder 9)
    Includes Plato Tracy Durham poem dedicated to A. B. Duke and excerpts from letters written to B. N. Duke in reaction to the poem.
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: clothing pattern (suit), undated; oversize (Box 123, Folder 12)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: funeral, 1929 January 10 (Box 136, Folder 10)
    Includes a church service program, lists of pallbearers and other funeral service participants, and a list of individuals who sent condolences to the family.
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: honorary degrees, 1926-1927; oversize (Box 123, Folder 13)
    Honorary degrees awarded to Benjamin N. Duke by Oglethorpe University and Lincoln Memorial University.
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: memorial album, 1929; oversize (Box 141)
    Telegrams and letters of condolence to family members, calling cards, and clippings on the death and legacy of Benjamin Newton Duke.
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: memorial resolution by The Duke Endowment (bound presentation copy), 1929 (Box 136, Folder 11)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: memorial service, Duke University, 1929 January 24; disbound album (Box 137, Folder 1)
    Includes program of exercises, prayer by Dr. M. Bradshaw, address by university president W. P. Few, resolution of the faculty, and 5 photographs from the funeral procession of B.N. Duke.
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: poetry volume with inscription to B.N. Duke from Jonathan C. Kilgo, 1907 (Box 137, Folder 2)
    A Morning Prayer and Other Beautiful Prayers by Robert Louis Stevenson, Dodge Publishing Company, New York, circa 1907. The inscription by Kilgo is dated Christmas 1907.
  - Duke, James B.: memorial resolution by the Piedmont and Northern Railway Company (bound presentation copy), 1926 (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Duke, Mary L. (Mary Duke Biddle): diploma, Trinity Park High School, 1903 June 6; oversize (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Duke, Mary L. (Mary Duke Biddle): Theatre record and scrapbook, 1898-1899 (Box 139)
    Impressions of and programs for twenty plays attended by Mary L. Duke (Mary Duke Biddle) with family and friends. Duke recorded information for each play according to the forms provided by the scrapbook publisher, with varying levels of completeness. The forms include fields for theater name, companions, seats, impressions of the play, criticism of the performance, and criticism of individual actors.
  - Duke, Sarah P.: diary, 1927 January 1-1929 January 5; 1 Volumes (Box 137, Folder 4)
    Sarah P. Duke's diary is "A Line A Day" notebook with very brief notes about activities, visitors, travel plans, weather, health of family members and friends, and other aspects of daily life.
  - Duke, Sarah P.: funeral, 1936 (Box 137, Folder 5)
    Copies of eulogy delivered by Dr. Ralph W. Sockman; typed and written lists of individuals who sent sympathy notes and flowers.
  - Duke, Sarah P.: recipes, circa 1880s-1930s and undated (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Duke, Sarah P.: recipes and cookbook, 1887 (Box 137, Folder 7)
    1887 edition of "Whitehead's family recipes." There are handwritten recipes inscribed at the front and back of the volume, presumably by Sarah P. Duke.
  - Genealogical information: Duke family, 1916-1937 and undated (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Lincoln Memorial University: Duke Hall of Citizenship dedication, 1927-1928 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Poetry, miscellanous, undated (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Printed material, circa 1880s, 1889, 1897-1908 (Box 138, Folder 4)
    Pamphlets, circulars, and other materials related to the social, religious, philanthropic and political interests of the Duke family.
  - Printed material, 1909-1913 (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Printed material, 1914-1915 (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Printed material, 1914-1929 and undated (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Printed material: The Orphan's Friend and Masonic Journal (Oxford, NC), 1902 June 27; oversize (Box 123, Folder 14)
  - Resolution of appreciation: guests at Carteret Lodge to Mr. and Mrs. B.N. Duke, 1903 January 1; oversize (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Resolution of thanks: Grand [Masonic] Lodge of North Carolina to Benjamin Newton Duke for service to Oxford Orphan Asylum, circa 1901 (Box 123, Folder 13)
  - Tributes: Benjamin N. Duke, 1923, 1928-1929 (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Tributes: Benjamin N. Duke: Chanticleer v. 2, 1913; 1 Volumes (Box 138, Folder 9)
  - Tributes: Benjamin Newton Duke on his birthday April 27, 1923, by Trinity College, vol. 1 (Volume 45)
    Vol. 1 contains a table of contents and congratulatory letters from Duke's friends and acquaintances.
  - Tributes: Benjamin Newton Duke on his birthday April 27, 1923, by Trinity College, vol. 2 (Volume 46)
    Vol. 2 contains photographs of the Trinity College campus.
- Pictures, circa 1877-1929, 1969, and undated; 3.75 Linear Feet
  The series begins with bound photograph albums, followed by images of people, and ends with images of places and buildings. The materials arranged alphabetically within each category.
  The Pictures series contains bound and disbound albums, photographs, and one mirror with attached photographs. Photographs of individuals and groups include Benjamin N. Duke, Sarah P. Duke, Angier B. Duke, Mary Duke Biddle, members of the extended family, and acquaintances. The series also contains photographs of buildings and places connected with the Duke family and its philanthropic efforts, including the Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah P. Duke family residence at Four Acres, Durham, NC, and structures and property connected to Trinity College.
  - Album I, circa 1870s-1890s (Box 142)
    Album I includes cabinet cards, mainly of individuals, with an index of known and probable photograph subjects. Individuals represented in the album include Woodward W. Duke (son of Brodie L. Duke), Angier Buchanan Duke, Sarah P. Duke, James Buchanan Duke, Sally Angier Duke, Lillie Irene Duke, James Edward Stagg, Benjamin Newton Duke, Mary E. (Duke) Lyon, Robert E. Lyon, Arthur H. Merritt, Malbourn Addison Angier, John Cicero Angier, Mary Angier Stokes, Inez Duke Angier (Stokes), Washington Duke (circa 1870s), Brodie L. Duke, and several other unidentified individuals, many of them infants and young children.
  - Album II, circa 1870s-1890s (Box 143)
    Album II contains cabinet cards, mainly of individuals, with an index of known and probable photograph subjects. Individuals represented include Bishop Charles Betts Galloway, Reverend William S. Black, Grover Cleveland, Frances Folsom Cleveland, Lida Duke Angier, Samuel Jones Angier, H. J. Bass (tobacconist), Benjamin Newton Duke, James Buchanan Duke, Angier Buchanan Duke, Mary E. (Duke) Lyon, Malbourn Addison Angier, Mary Lillian Duke (Biddle), Maude Duke (Karnes), and several unidentified individuals.
  - Album II: Loose photographs removed from album II, 4 items (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - [Album III], circa 1890s-1920s (Box 144)
    This album includes pictures of Cordelia Drexel Biddle Duke and her children, Angier Biddle Duke and Anthony Drexel Duke, and various unidentified individuals.
  - Duke, Angier Buchanan, circa 1890s-1915; 4 items (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Duke, Benjamin N., circa 1870s-1880s; 2 items (Box 145, Folder 3)
    Cabinet card prints by Anderson's of New York, NY.
  - Duke, Benjamin N., circa 1890s-1910s; 5 items (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - Duke, Benjamin N., circa 1920s; 8 items (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: oval print, circa 1892-1897; Print attached to fragile, convex glass. (Box 162)
    Fragile--please ask for staff assistance in handling this item.
    Possibly an anniversary portrait.
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and family, circa 1890s; 1 items (Box 145, Folder 6)
    Group photograph of Benjamin N. Duke, Sarah P. Duke, James B. Duke, Angier B. Duke, Mary L. Duke (Mary Duke Biddle), and unidentified woman in front of a house.
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and Mary L. Duke (Mary Duke Biddle), circa 1890s; 1 items (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and others: Boardwalk, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1924; 7 items (Box 145, Folder 8)
    Individuals pictured include James Buchanan Duke, Benjamin Newton Duke, Mary Duke Biddle, Robert Lee Flowers, and Lily Parrish Flowers. The notes on back of photographs were written by Dr. Lenox Baker (son-in-law of R. and L. Flowers).
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and others, Lookout Mountain, Tennessee, 1892; 3 items (Box 145, Folder 9)
    These photographs were taken at Point Lookout and Sunset Rock. See Correspondence series: J. J. Ingalls to B. N. Duke, November 9, 1892.
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and Sarah P. Duke, St. Petersburg, Florida, 1914; 1 items (Box 145, Folder 10)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: funeral, Durham, NC: photographs and program of exercises, 1929 January (Box 145, Folder 11)
    The photographs depict the funeral procession from Duke Memorial Church and its spectators along Chapel Hill Street, Durham, North Carolina; students and faculty honoring Duke at Duke University (East Campus); and the Duke family mausoleum in Maplewood Cemetery. The program of exercises includes the address by President W. P. Few, resolutions of the faculty of Duke University, and a prayer by Dr. M. Bradshaw.
  - Duke, Cordelia Biddle and children (Angier Biddle Duke and Anthony Drexel Duke), with Mary Duke Biddle, circa 1920; 3 items (Box 145, Folder 12)
  - Duke family birthday party, New York, NY, circa 1916; 2 items (Box 145, Folder 13)
    Individuals pictured include Benjamin N. Duke, Sarah P. Duke, Anthony Drexel Biddle, and various unidentified adults and children. According to note accompanying photograph, the picture was taken inside the house at 2 E. 82nd Street, New York, NY.
  - Duke, James B.: funeral procession, Durham, NC, 1925; print of Underwood and Underwood portrait, circa 1920s, 2 items (Box 145, Folder 14)
  - Duke, Mary L. (Mary Duke Biddle), circa 1896-1907; 3 items (Box 145, Folder 15)
  - Duke, Sarah P., circa 1870s-1920s; 9 items (Box 145, Folder 16)
    Includes a photograph of Sarah P. Duke in a coach with children Angier B. Duke and Mary L. Duke (Mary Duke Biddle), circa 1888-1890.
  - Duke, Sarah P.: oval print, circa 1892-1897; Print attached to fragile, convex glass. (Box 162)
  - Duke, Sarah P., 1892?; 2 items; oversize (Box 123, Folder 1)
    Full-length photographs, possibly taken for the fifteenth wedding anniversary of Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah P. Duke (1892).
  - Duke, Sarah P., 1906, circa 1910s; 2 items; oversize (Box 123, Folder 2)
    Portrait by the Halladay Studio, Durham, NC (1906), and an undated portrait by the Lafayette studio in London.
  - Duke, Washington and family: mirror with photographs, undated; fragile (Box 147)
    Cut-out images of Washington Duke, Brodie L. Duke, James B. Duke, Benjamin N. Duke, and Mary E. Duke (Mary Duke Lyon) under glass layer of framed mirror. Photographs circa 1870s.
  - Duke, Washington with great-grandchildren, circa 1900; oversize (Box 148, Folder 1)
    The children pictured are likely those of Mary Washington Lyon Stagg and James Edward Stagg.
  - People, miscellaneous or unidentified, circa 1880s-1890s and undated; 6 items (Box 145, Folder 17)
    Individuals represented include Reuben Oscar Everett and others outside the White House, Washington, DC; James Acero Angier, circa 1880s; James Haywood Southgate, circa 1890s; and other unidentified persons.
  - Photographs by Professor Marquis H. Lockwood (Trinity College), 4 items (Box 145, Folder 18)
    Lockwood was a Physics and Biology professor who experimented with photography. His "trick" photographs include "Frog Pond," Professor Jerome Dowd playing chess with himself, and a composite of four views of Mary Lillian Duke (Mary Duke Biddle). Also included is a photograph of the Moses Hester church [Berea Christian Church] and house in Durham, NC.
  - Portraits (photographs of) by Sir Joshua Reynolds, 2 items (Box 145, Folder 19)
  - Artelia Roney Duke birthplace; Stonewall Springs and Boyd's Creek, Alamance County, NC, circa 1920s; 2 items (Box 145, Folder 20)
  - Bassett-Brown House, Trinity College, Durham, NC, circa 1912; 1 items (Box 145, Folder 21)
    The house, located on N. Buchanan Blvd., was first occupied by Professor J. S. Bassett and later by Frank C. Brown
  - Carriage house and stable (engraving), H. J. Blauvelt, Architect, for B.N. Duke, Durham, NC, circa 1901; 4 items (Box 145, Folder 22)
  - Duke's Chapel construction, Braggtown, Durham, NC, 1926 November; 8 items (Box 145, Folder 23)
    The photographs depict the partially-built structure of the church (designed by the firm of Horace Trumbauer) and construction workers in the foreground.
  - Duke Quarry near Hillsborough, North Carolina; Duke Forest, Durham, NC; New Hope River [New Hope Creek], Durham and Orange Counties, NC, circa 1926; 15 items (Box 145, Folder 24)
    These prints related to the construction of Duke University West Campus were sent by Frank C. Brown to Benjamin N. Duke, with an accompanying letter. They include photographs of the site for the "new buildings" (Duke University West Campus?) and the site of new highway through Duke University property.
  - Duke University: East Campus construction, circa 1925; 6 items (Box 145, Folder 25)
    These photographs depict the excavation, grading, and tree removal related to construction of new East Campus buildings. Individuals pictured include Robert L. Flowers and Frank C. Brown, laborers and various onlookers. Also pictured are the original library and Alspaugh residence hall, which were relocated to Kittrell College, North Carolina.
  - Fairview (home of Washington Duke), Durham, NC, circa 1890s; 2 items (Box 145, Folder 26)
  - Four Acres, Durham, NC: exteriors, after 1910; 9 items (Box 145, Folder 27)
  - Four Acres, Durham, NC: exteriors, after 1910; 5 items; copy negatives (Box 145, Folder 28)
  - Four Acres, Durham, NC: exteriors, circa 1910; disbound album, 1 of 2 (Box 148, Folder 2)
  - Four Acres, Durham, NC: exteriors, circa 1910; disbound album, 2 of 2 (Box 148, Folder 3)
  - Four Acres, Durham, NC: interiors, circa 1910; disbound album, 1 of 2 (Box 148, Folder 4)
  - Four Acres, Durham, NC: interiors, circa 1910; disbound album, 2 of 2 (Box 148, Folder 5)
  - Irvington-on-the-Hudson estate (Linden Court), Tarrytown, NY, undated; 4 items (Box 146, Folder 1)
  - Kittrell College: B.N. Duke Library, 1969 September; 2 items; color 35 mm slides (Box 146, Folder 2)
  - Limestone College, Gaffney, SC, 1926; 3 items (Box 146, Folder 3)
    These photographs depict a parade celebrating Benjamin N. Duke's endowment gift to the college.
  - ["Sarmiento," Mary Duke Biddle house in Florida?], undated; 1 items (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - Trollinger Family Cemetery (Haw River Methodist Church), Alamance County, NC (burial place of Artelia Roney Duke), circa 1924-1929; 3 items (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - Underpass, Chapel Hill Street, Durham, NC: Construction, 1926 June; 8 items (Box 146, Folder 6)
    These photographs include views of "The Terrace" (the former Duke residence that was relocated for the construction of Four Acres), the Southgate Jones House, and other buildings, workers and equipment.
  - University United Methodist Church, Chapel Hill, NC, after 1924; 3 items (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - YWCA building, intersection of Gregson Street and Chapel Hill Street, Durham, NC, 1927; 5 items (Box 146, Folder 8)
- Duke Farm, University Station, NC, 1891-1919; 2.25 Linear Feet
  General
  Deeds and blueprint land plats of Orange County, NC property owned by Benjamin N. Duke are located in the Legal Series.
  Materials in the Duke Farm series include correspondence, financial documents, a hand-colored land plat, and photographs related to the farm that Benjamin N. Duke owned in Orange County, NC. The letters are mainly between the successive farm superintendents employed by Duke, including J.T. Hogan, I. A. Hogan, and Weldon Riley, and J. E. Stagg and E. A. Childs, Duke's financial agents in Durham, NC. Other correspondents include equipment and agricultural suppliers and contractors.
  Topics represented in the series include requests for money and instructions on farm management; the purchase of implements, machinery and livestock; the construction of barns and other farm improvements; and requests for farm products to be delivered to Duke's Durham house and other locations. There is also scattered correspondence related to the finances and health of the Hogan family.
  - Correspondence, 1891-1909; 15 folders (Box 149)
  - Correspondence, 1910-1916, 1918-1919; 9 folders (Box 150)
  - Construction payrolls and invoices, 1894-1895; 2 folders (Box 150)
  - Hogan residence specifications, undated (Box 150)
  - Account book: farm expenditures, 1897-1909; 1 Volumes (Box 150)
  - Monthly expenditure statements, 1901 July-1910; 2 folders (Box 150)
  - Monthly expenditure statements, 1911-1917; 7 folders (Box 151)
  - Land plat: B.N. Duke Farm, Orange County, NC, 1897?; oversize (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1910-1919 and undated (Box 152)
- Richard B. Arrington, 1905-1914; 2 Linear Feet
  The correspondence is arranged chronologically, followed by the letterbook and finanical papers.
  The Richard B. Arrington series is composed of the personal papers of Benjamin Newton Duke's personal secretary and business agent, who worked in the New York office. This series includes letters, letterbook, accounts, check stubs, and receipts. The correspondence covers two periods: 1903-1907 and 1911-1914. From 1903 to 1907 the major focus is building and furnishing a house on Ridgeview Road in White Plains, N.Y. From 1911 the emphasis is on Arrington's business interests, including stock transactions and insurance. Since Arrington died April 17, 1913, the remainder of the correspondence (1913-1914) concerns his estate. His wife, Ethel Lewis Arrington, carried on much of the estate's business. The accounts, check stubs and receipts pertain to Arrington's general business activities; the major focus is on stock transactions especially of the Piedmont Syndicate. Much of his business parallels his work for Benjamin Newton Duke.
  - Correspondence, 1905 November 9-1914 April; 11 folders (Box 153)
  - Letterbook, 1903 December 16-1906 August 3 (Box 154)
  - Financial accounts, 1907-1913; 2 Linear Feet (Box 155)
  - Check stubs, 1913 March-April (Box 155)
  - Receipts, 1905-1913; 2 folders (Box 155)
- Alexander H. Sands, Jr., 1910-1918; 2.5 Linear Feet
  The materials in this series document the personal and financial interests of Alexander H. Sands, Jr., a secretary and business agent for Benjamin N. Duke in New York, NY. The series includes letters, letterbooks, account book, check registers, check stubs, a daybook, ledger and receipts. The correspondence, 1910-1918, primarily concerns Sands's family matters and personal business interests. He also supported both his parents, Mary Harvey Sands and Tucker K. Sands. The remainder of Sands's papers details stock transactions and other business activities, including those of the Southern Audit Company of New York, Inc., of which Sands was a partner.
  The correspondence is arranged chronologically, followed by the letterbooks and finanical papers.
  - Correspondence, 1910 April-1914 April (Box 155)